Pribram, Karl; Papers ger005
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Karl Pribram Papers
1877-1973
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger005
10 cubic ft.
Karl Pribram was an emigre economist from Austria and an expert on economic thought and policymaking. The Pribram Papers include diaries, documents, correspondence, manuscripts, notes and Pribram's publications.
Biographical History
Karl Pribram (1877-1973) was an Austrian-born economist who held important positions before and during World War I in the Austrian government, with the International Labour Office in Geneva in the 1920s, and after his emigration to the United States in 1934, with the Brookings Institution in Washington, D.C., the U.S. Social Security Board and the U.S. Tariff Commission. Dr. Pribram also lectured at the University of Vienna, was Professor of Economics at the University of Frankfurt am Main from 1928 to 1933, and later at American University in Washington, D.C.
Pribram's extensive writings cover topics in labor economics, industrial organization and in the history of economic thought. His works include Unification of Social Insurance (1925), Cartel Problems; An Analysis of Collective Monopolies in Europe with American Application (1935), Social Insurance in Europe and Social Security in the United States (1937), Foreign Trade Policy of Austria (1945), Conflicting Patterns of Thought (1949), and his posthumously published A History of Economic Reasoning (1983). Pribram has been described by Nobel Laureate Friedrich A. Hayek as "without exception the most learned man in the field"
Chronology of Events
1877 Born on December 2 in Prague, Czechoslovakia to Otto and Leonore Popper Pribram.
1895 Graduated from the Deutsches Staats-Gymnasium, Prague.
1895-1900 Studied law at the University of Prague.
1900 Received Dr. jur. from the University of Prague.
1900-1902 Practiced law
1902-1907 Studied social sciences, economics at the Universities of Berlin and Vienna.
1907 Habilitation in political economics at the University of Vienna.
1909-1921 Worked as statistician in the Austrian Civil Service (Wirtschaftsstatistik, Statistische Zentralkommission), eventually earning the title of Ministerialrat.
1914 Earned title of Professor, University of Vienna.
1919-1921 Chief of the Legislative Division for Social Policy in the Austrian Ministry for Social Administration.
1921-1928 Head of the Statistical Section of the International Office of Labor, Geneva, Switzerland.
1928-1933 Professor of economics, University of Frankfurt am Main, Germany.
1929 Married Edith Körnei on April 4.
1933 Set sail from Hamburg, Germany on the S. S. Manhattan on December 15.
1924 Receives degrees of Pol.Sc.D. and LL.D. from Halle, June 20
1934 Arrived in New York
1934-1936 Member of the research staff of the Brookings Institute, Washington, D.C.
1936-1942 Served as Senior Economic Expert on the U. S. Social Security Board.
1939-1952 Adjunct Professor of Economics at American University, Washington, D.C.
1942-1951 Served as Senior Economist at the U.S. Tariff Commission.
1973 Died on July 14 in Washington, D.C.
Scope and Contents
The Karl Pribram Papers consist of 10 cubic feet of materials, 1877-1973, and include diaries, documents, correspondence, manuscripts, notes and publications of Karl Pribram. The bulk of the collection consists of Pribram's writings, both in manuscript and published form, on labor, housing, unemployment and the history of economic thought. His papers include writings intended for publication as well as memoranda generated by Pribram during his years at the U.S. Social Security Board and the U.S. Tariff Commission.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into seven series:
Series 1: Diaries and notebooks, 1945-1971
Series 2: Biographical materials and documents, 1883-1949
Series 3: Correspondence, 1900-1958
Series 4: Correspondence and memoranda related to Pribram's positions, 1933-1947
Series 5: Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lecture notes, 1923-1952
Series 6: Publications of Karl Pribram, 1904-1951
Series 7: Publications by others
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the estate of Edith Pribram, the widow of Karl Pribram, in January 1989.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Economics; Economics -- Study and teaching.; Economists -- Austria.; Economists -- United States.; Austrians -- United States.; Social security -- United States.; Health insurance -- Study and teaching.; Rent (Economic theory); Social security -- Austria.; Pribram, Karl, 1877-1973.; Austria. Ministry of Commerce.; Austria. Ministry for Social Administration.; International Labour Office.
- Diaries and notebooks, 1945-1971; 1; 1 cubic ft. 30 items
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains 28 appointment diaries, one for each year (1945-1971), detailing Pribram's daily activities. There are also 2 additional small format notebooks, one for a trip to Paris, July 25-September 12, 1961.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
- Biographical materials and documents, 1883-1949; 2; 7 file folders
  This series consists of documents, including extensive school records, correspondence relating to positions held by Pribram, and some early clippings about him.
  - Documents, 1877-1929 (Box 2 (2-Biographical materials and documents), Folder 1)
    Including birth and marriage certificates, early curriculum vitae, early contracts.
  - Gymnasium and university records, 1883-1901 (Box 2 (2-Biographical materials and documents), Folder 2)
  - Documents and correspondence concerning employment, 1905-1928 (Box 2 (2-Biographical materials and documents), Folder 3)
  - Documents and correspondence, University of Frankfurt, 1929-1933 (Box 2 (2-Biographical materials and documents), Folder 4)
  - Employment records from the United States Tariff Commission, 1942-1949 (Box 2 (2-Biographical materials and documents), Folder 5)
  - Hand X-ray, 1942 (Box 2 (2-Biographical materials and documents), Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings and other printed materials about Pribram, 1917-1934 (Box 2 (2-Biographical materials and documents), Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1900-1958; 3; 46 file folders
  This series contains scattered correspondence over the years concerning publications as well as with other economists and scholars including Peter Drucker, Josef Dunner, Hans Kelsen and Emil Lederer.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Drafts of early letters by Pribram, 1922-1923 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Frankfurt am Main, 1929-1930 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - American Economic Association, 1953 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - American Statistical Association, 1937 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - The American University, 1940 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Beede, K. C. (Federal Housing Administration), 1936 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Bien, Bettina, 1958 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Blelloch, David H. (International Housing Office), 1942 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Cowles, Alfred (Cowles Commission for Research in Economics), 1938 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Drucker, Peter, 1929 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Dunner, Josef, 1942; Undated (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - The Econometric Society, 1939 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Economics of Urban Housing (Leo Grehler, Ronald Press Company), 1939-1940 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Foreign Affairs (Hamilton Fish Armstrong), 1942 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Goodrich, Carter, 1942 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Grünberg, Carl, 1918; 1926 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Guradze, Heinz, 1951 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Haberler, Gottfried, 1953; draft (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Kelsen, Hans, 1929 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Klein, Franz, 1914 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Knight, Frank H., 1952 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Lederer, Emil, 1930 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Lemmer, Fr, 1932 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Lorwin, Val R., 1936 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Meyer, Fred, 1948 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Montgomery, Royal E., 1934 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Morse, Wayne, 1946 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research (Frederick C. Mills), 1936 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - Nelson, Alfred C., 1941 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Palla, Edmund, 1946 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - Piquet, Howard S., 1952 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - Pleskot, Jiri, 1938 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Pribram, Bruno, 1945 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Pribram, John, 1944; 1946 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Pribram, Otto, 1942; 1946 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - Price, Albert L., 1940 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Rauchberg, Heinrich, 1912; 1918; 1929 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - The Review of Economic Statistics, 1937 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Rice, Stuart A., 1940-1941 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Richter, Hans, Undated (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Schlesinger, Charlotte, 1941 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Schoenbaum, Emil, 1945 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 49)
  - Siebrecht, Valentin, 1948 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 50)
  - Sommer, Luise, 1913 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 51)
  - Spielmans, John V., 1945 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 52)
  - Stern, Carl S., 1938 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 53)
  - Miscellaneous, 1900-1949 (Box 2 (3-Correspondence), Folder 54)
- Correspondence and memoranda related to Pribram's positions, 1933-1947; 4; 7 file folders
  This series contains correspondence and shorter memoranda generated by Pribram and other members of the agencies where Pribram worked, including the Institut International de Statistique (1933-1935), the U.S. Social Security Board (1935-1942) and the U.S. Tariff Commission (1942-1951).
  - Institut International de Statistique (incl. W. H. Methorst, Wesley C. Mitchell, Walter F. Willcox), 1933-1936 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence and memoranda related to Pribram's ), Folder 55)
  - Institut International de Statistique, 1937-1938 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence and memoranda related to Pribram's ), Folder 56)
  - Institut International de Statistique. Visitor's book, 1929 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence and memoranda related to Pribram's ), Folder 57)
  - United States Social Security Board (incl. W. Ellison Chalmers, Ewan Clague, Gladys Friedman, Mary Ross, Collis Stocking, W. R. Williamson), 1937-1940 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence and memoranda related to Pribram's ), Folder 58)
  - United States Social Security Board (incl. Louis, Levine, W. Woytinsky), 1941-1942 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence and memoranda related to Pribram's ), Folder 59)
  - United States Tariff Commission (incl. Lewis L. Lorwin, L. Morrison), 1942-1947 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence and memoranda related to Pribram's ), Folder 60)
  - Scientific Conference on Interpreting and Inter-cultural Barriers to Communication, 1956 January 4 (Box 2 (4-Correspondence and memoranda related to Pribram's ), Folder 61)
    Conference proceedings.
- Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lecture notes, 1923-1952; 5; 85 file folders
  This series contains manuscripts, typescripts and notes for published articles and lectures, as well as some longer studies prepared by Pribram during his years at the U.S. Social Security Board and the U.S. Tariff Commission.
  - "A Short History of the International Labor Organization Center", 1947 February 7 (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 62)
  - "The American system of social security and the European systems of social insurance: A comparative study", 1937 January 28 (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 63)
  - "Balance of Payments Position of the United Kingdom as affected by the war", 1945 October (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 64)
  - Cartel Problems. Preface, 1936 (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 65)
  - "Compensation for Unemployment During Industrial Disputes", 1940 (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 66)
  - "Considerations on the proposed Survey and Appraisal of Post-War Plans", 1942 September (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 67)
  - "Digest from E. F. Penrose, Freedom from Want -- A suggested Program", Undated (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 68)
  - "Duration of Benefits and Unemployment Compensation Policy", Undated (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 69)
  - "Economic and Constitutional Limitations to Social Programs", 1936 February 17 (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 70)
  - "Economic Policy and Development in Austria, 1815-1848". Seminar text, The Johns Hopkins University, 1939 January (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 71)
  - Economics of Housing. Lecture notes, 1942 (Box 2 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 72-73)
  - "Economics of Urban Housing. A Handbook". Outlines for a proposed volume, ca. 1941 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 1)
  - "Eligibility Requirements", Undated; manuscript (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 2)
  - "Excess Reserves and Deficit Financing in Employment Compensation" (written with Gardner F. Derrickson), 1940 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 3)
  - "Factors Affecting the International Trade Policies of Foreign Countries After the War", 1945 April (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 4)
  - "Foreign Trade Positions of Other Countries", 1946 April (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 5)
  - "From the Classical to the Scholastic School", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 6)
  - "The Historical Background of the Benefit Formula in Unemployment Compensation", 1939 February (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 7)
  - "A History of Economic Reasoning", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 8)
    Typescripts, notes.
  - Economic Reasoning. Lecture notes, Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 9-10)
  - "Economic Reasoning". Round table discussion, papers by participants: R. C. Callender, Alexander Gall, George Gussman, Charles J. Horan, R. Lutz, 1940 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 11)
  - "Gleichgewichtsvorstellungen in der Konjunkturtheorie", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 12)
  - Housing and Home Financing. Lecture notes, American University, 1935-1936 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 13)
  - "Housing Policy and the Defense Program", 1941 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 14)
  - "How can future wars be prevented?", 1942; manuscript (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 15)
  - "If you had $25,000.- to spend for the improvement of American statistics, how would you use it?", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 16)
  - "The International Aspects of Chemical Nitrogen", 1944 September (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 17)
  - "International Aspects of the Potash Industry", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 18)
  - "The International Labor Organization, its present functions and future tasks", 1942 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 19)
  - "International Wirtschaftspolitik und Internationale Sozialpolitik". Handwritten notes, galley proofs, 1928 November 24 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 20)
  - "The Labor Dispute Disqualification", 1941 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 21)
  - "Limits of Local Autonomy in Employment Exchange Operations", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 22)
  - The McCormack Amendment. Texts and related correspondence, 1939-1940 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 23)
  - "The Notion of 'Economic System' Underlying Business Cycle Analysis", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 24)
  - "Patterns of Commercial Policy", 1945 April 24 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 25)
  - "Patterns of Economic Reasoning". Paper for the American Economic Association, 1952 December (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 26)
  - Post-War German problems, 1941-1942 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 27)
    Manuscripts, notes.
  - "Un principe constructeur de la vie sociale moderne", 1923 April 6 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 28)
  - "The Problem of Collective Monopolies", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 29)
  - "Problems of Employment During the War and the Post-war Periods", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 30)
  - "Problems of Seasonal Employment", 1937 December 1 (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 31)
  - "Problems to be discussed by an Unemployment Compensation Advisory Committee", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 32)
  - "Reasons for Proposed Board Requirements of Benefit Statistics", Undated (Box 3 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 33)
  - "Recovery Policies and Recovery Measures", 1936 (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 1-2)
  - "Report on Experience Rating", 1938 December 2 (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 3)
  - "Six Lectures on Labor Problems". Harvard University lectures, 1934 (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 4)
  - "Social Budgeting". Lecture, 1940 (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 5)
  - "Some Dynamic Aspects of the Urban Ground Rent", Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 6)
  - "Some Economic and Social Problems in Health Insurance", 1936 (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 7)
  - "Some Economic Aspects of the Housing Problem". Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 8)
  - "Study of the Solvency of State Unemployment Compensation Funds, 1932-1941", 1941 November (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 9)
  - Study on German Exchange Control, 1942 (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 10)
  - "Survey of documents on cartelization supplied by the Department of Justice", 1943 November 6 (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 11)
  - "Die Mausefalle" / "Tea Without Sugar". Playscript in German and English. Geneva, 1920s (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 12)
  - Typescript fragments, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 13)
  - "Deletions", Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 14)
    Note slips, typed passages.
  - "Last chapters". Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 15)
  - Notes to lectures, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 16)
  - Business cycles. Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 17)
  - Competition, Monopolies. Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 18)
  - Economic Method. Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 19)
  - Economic Reasoning. Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 20)
  - English and German phrases. Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 21)
  - International Organizations. Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 22)
  - International Trade. Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 23)
  - Kapitalismus. Notes in German, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 24)
  - Keynes. Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 25)
  - Monetary / Price Theory. Notes, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 26)
  - Notverordnungen der Reichsregierung. Notes in German, Undated (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 27)
  - Seminar notes, 1929-1930 (Box 4 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 28)
  - Socialism in the USSR. Notes, Undated (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 1)
  - Sozialpolitik. Notes in German, 1929; 1932 (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 2)
  - Sweden -- welfare. Notes, Undated (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 3)
  - Theorie -- Politik, Weltwirtschaft. Notes in German, Undated (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 4)
  - Welfare economics. Notes, Undated (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 5)
  - Wirtschaftspolitik. Notes in German, Undated (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 6)
  - World trade. Notes in German. Frankfurt am Main, 1929 (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 7)
  - Varia. Notes, Undated (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 8-9)
  - Notes removed from books, Undated (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous notebooks, Undated (Box 5 (5-Manuscripts and typescripts; notes, including lect), Folder 11-12)
- Publications of Karl Pribram, 1904-1951; 6; 192 file folders
  This series contains a nearly complete collection of Pribram's essayistic writings and reviews, as well as proofs and unbound versions of several of his books.
  - Bound volume containing articles on housing, 1908-1931(?) (Box 5 (6-Publications of Karl Pribram), Folder 13)
  - Bound volume containing articles, 1912-1928 (Box 5 (6-Publications of Karl Pribram), Folder 14)
  - Bound volume containing articles on Sozialpolitik, 1921-1926 (Box 5 (6-Publications of Karl Pribram), Folder 15)
  - Bound volume containing articles from the periodical Soziale Praxis, 1920 (Box 5 (6-Publications of Karl Pribram), Folder 16)
  - Bound volume containing articles from the periodical Soziale Praxis, 1925-1928 (Box 5 (6-Publications of Karl Pribram), Folder 17)
  - Bound volume containing articles from the periodical Soziale Praxis, 1929-1933 (Box 5 (6-Publications of Karl Pribram), Folder 18)